TONI ANEV

Results driven data analyst with a passion for analytics and process automation. A self-starter who enjoys the challenge of complex technical problems and is able to aggregate, condense and communicate complex insights in clear and accessible ways.

Extensive experience working with large-scale data sets, programming languages and visualization tools in both research and business environments. Relentlessly curious and driven to learn about emerging technologies and dive deep into the intricacies of how things work behind the scenes.

EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYST, LOBLAW COMPANIES LTD

Toronto, Canada | January 2019 – Present

- Designed, tested and productionized an automated analytical model aimed at maximizing department revenue by forecasting optimal product pricing and markdown timing using SQL, Python and Apache Spark in Azure HDInsight.
- Worked closely with senior leadership to optimize current decisioning processes, conduct impact analyses and integrate analytical model resulting in an incremental profit increase of \$15-20M (~25% improvement) annually.
- Develop data pipelines related to media campaign delivery and insight gathering from Facebook Business Manager and Google DV360 aimed at increasing department revenue by 42M annually.
- Design customer attribution and segmentation models aimed at leveraging proprietary transactional data and existing partnerships with Facebook, Google and Adobe to deliver scalable and highly personalized advertising to customers.
- Implement methodologies that empower senior leadership and key decision makers with weekly performance metrics relating to sell through rates, revenue projections, price elasticities and markdown suggestions.
- Work cross-functionally to solve high impact business problems and support the development of reporting insights gathered from various data warehouses such as Hadoop, Azure and Google Cloud Platform (GCP).

DATA ANALYST, NUMERIS

Toronto, Canada | September 2016 – January 2019

- Designed Python and PL/SQL scripts to automate data extraction, wrangling and error checking processes resulting in +90% processing efficiency.
- Designed PL/SQL scripts to manage system generated work orders by inserting and updating action/state codes into normalized production database, automating 10 days of work effort across 2 departments.
- Automated report generation of employee performance metrics and panelist behavior insights using Python and PL/SQL resulting in +95% process efficiency.
- Performed in depth analysis of national research sample data to optimize universe rim weighting changes, population demographic updates, reception type updates and geographic cell changes.
- Worked cross-functionally with teams to identify business and research requirements leading to the development of KPIs, insight reports and database security updates.

RESEARCH ANALYST, *UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO, FACULTY OF MEDICINE* Toronto, Canada | 2014 – 2015

- Cleansed, organized and analyzed faculty research data to help leaders make informed funding decisions.
- Prepared reports and communication for senior management to ensure relevant and consistent internal communications.
- Created and presented visualizations to senior leadership relating to researcher collaboration metrics and overall department research focus areas.

github:

www.github.com/tonianev

linkedin:

www.linkedin.com/in/tonianev

EDUCATION

Data Scientist Nanodegree

Udacity Inc. | 2019

Data Analyst Nanodegree

Udacity Inc. | 2018

Bachelor of Science

McMaster University | 2012 - 16

Health Information Management

George Brown College | 2010 - 11

EXPERTISE

Python (pandas, numpy, django etc.)
SQL (Oracle, Teradata, BigQuery etc.)
Tableau / Cytoscape / Matplotlib
Node.js / Express.js / Mongo DB
Databricks / Jupyter / Spyder
Hadoop / Spark / Eagle Eye
R (knitr, ggplot2, dplyr etc.)
HTML5 / CSS / JavaScript
Azure/ GCP / AWS
Git / Bitbucket

CERTIFICATIONS

Machine Learning, Data Science and Deep Learning with Python

Udemy | 2019 Course Certificate

Machine Learning A-Z: Python & R in Data Science

Udemy | 2018 Course Certificate

Web Developer Bootcamp

Udemy | 2017 Course Certificate

AWARDS

Entrance Scholarship Recipient

McMaster University, 2012

Honors for Academic Excellence

Burnhamthorpe Collegiate Institute, 2012

Honors for Academic Excellence

Martingrove Collegiate Institute, 2010